Colliders are a component that allows
コライダとは、
the game object they're attached to
ゲームオブジェクトにアタッチすると
to react to other colliders
他のコライダに反応するコンポーネントであり、
provided that one of the game objects
そのためには衝突するゲームオブジェクトのいどちらかが
has a rigidbody component attached.
Rigidbody コンポーネントがアタッチされている必要があります。
Colliders come in various shapes and types,
コライダには様々な形状や種類があり、
and are denoted in the scene view
緑色のラインに囲われて
by a green outline.
シーンビューで描画されます。
They can have the following primitive shapes:
形状は次に挙げるプリミティブ (原始図形) のいずれかです:
a sphere, a capsule and a box.
Sphere, Capsule, Box です。
For more complex shapes you have two options
より複雑な形状には二つのオプションがあります。
You can either combine several of these
これらのプリミティブ形状のいずれかを
primitive shapes together by applying
組み合わせるために、別のオブジェクトに
primitive colliders to different objects.
プリミティブ コライダを Hierarchy 上で
in our hierarchy.
適用します。
For example this workbench
この workbench オブジェクトには
has a number of objects which simply
複数のオブジェクトがあり、
serve to make up it's different colliders
いくつかのエリアの
for various areas.
別のコライダからなっています。
The other option is to use a mesh collider,
もうひとつのオプションはメッシュ コライダを使用することであり、
which will fit the exact shape of the
これにより指定したメッシュの形状に
mesh that you specify.
完全に一致します。
The workbench on the right has no hierarchy
右の workbench オブジェクトには階層はなく
but instead uses a mesh collider.
その代わりにメッシュ コライダを使用します。
The reason not to use a mesh collider
メッシュ コライダを使用しない理由は、
is that it will fit the exact shape
指定したメッシュの形状と完全に
of the mesh that you specify. So if you
一致するためです。
only specify the mesh of your detailed model
つまり、複雑なモデルのメッシュを指定すると
then it may be providing too detailed
複雑すぎるコリジョン メッシュを提供するかもしれず
a collision mesh and effecting performance.
パフォーマンスに影響します。
This is the reason why it's often better
複合的なセットアップを使用したほうが
to make a compound setup instead.
良い理由はこのためです。
However it should be noted that a third
しかしコリジョンする物体を作成するには
option for creating collision geometry
3 つめの選択肢があり、
is to use a separate, simpler set of
別のよりシンプルな物体に修正して
geometry and still use a mesh collider.
メッシュ コライダを使用する方法です。
In this example we have this complex
この例では、複雑なロボット アームの
robot arm asset.
アセットがあります。
It's a very detailed mesh
これは非常に複雑なメッシュですが
but we don't want a mesh as complex
衝突の際にここまで複雑な
as this for the collisions.
メッシュは必要ではありません。
So what we've done is built
ここでは
a secondary set of geometry which we've
二個目の物体のセットを作成して
then applied to a series of mesh colliders.
一連のメッシュ コライダに適用してます。
For example this part of the claw is more
例えば爪のこの部分は
detailed than the collision mesh
そのために作成したコリジョン メッシュよりも
that we've created for it.
複雑です。
And this has been done in two separate
二つの別の FBX ファイルで行われてます。
FBX files -The original artwork and
元のモデル作品と物体をローポリにした物体の
a simplified set of geometry.
二つです。
We've then gone through each one,
それから各々をみていって、
applied a mesh collider and dragged
メッシュ コライダを適用して
these meshes over as the
使用するコリジョン メッシュとして
collision meshes to use.
ドラッグしてます。
This means that we get the kind of accuracy
整理するとパフォーマンスのオーバーヘッドなく
that we need in terms of collision
衝突という意味で必要な正確性が
without the performance overhead.
得られるということです。
When collisions occur in the game engine
ゲームエンジンで衝突が起こるとき
one collider strikes another and an event
ひとつのコライダが別のものと衝突して、
called OnCollisionEnter is called.
OnCollisionEnter がコールされます。
In this scene our 'prop samoflange' object
このシーンにおいて prop samoflange オブジェクトには
has a sphere collider component and a rigidbody component.
別の Sphere Collider コンポーネントおよび Rigidbody コンポーネントがあります。
The rigidbody provides mass and gravity.
Rigidbody は重量(mass)および重力(gravity)を提供します。
When I play the game, one falls down
ゲームを再生するとき、ひとつが
and strikes the other.
倒れて、もう片方に衝突します。
The power cube has a box collider attached to it.
powerCube は Box Collider がアタッチされています。
Also attached to our falling object
これは 落下するオブジェクトにも
is this script.
アタッチされています。
This script checks for three collision events.
スクリプトは三つの衝突イベントを検知します。
OnCollisionEnter, OnCollisionStay
OnCollisionEnter, OnCollisionStay  および
and OnCollisionExit.
OnCollisionExit です。
When each of these occurs it writes
これらの 各々が発生するとき、
to the console using Debug.Log.
Debug.Log を使用してコンソールに書き込みを行ないます。
It will register when Enter is called,
Enter がコールされたとき、
when Stay is occurring
Stay が発生したとき、
and when Exit is called.
また、Exit がコールされたときに登録されます。
So if we look at our console you can see
もしコンソールをみれば
that Enter is called, Stay has occurred
Enter がコールされたか、Stay がしばらくの間発生したか、
for a while and then Exit is called.
また、Exit がコールされたか確認することが出来ます。
If we pause the game and play we can look
もしゲームをポーズして再生すると、
at this example slowly.
このサンプルをゆっくりと眺めることが出来ます。
As I step through the frames
コリジョンが発生したときに
when the collision occurs you can see
フレームごとにステップ実行すると
that Enter is called, so OnCollisionEnter
OnCollisionEnter がコールされているので、OnCollisionEnter は
has just occurred.
発生した直後です。
As I continue OnCollisionStay is occurring.
その後続けると、OnCollisionStay が発生しています。
You can see on the right here that it's
この右側で、
happening several times because these
二つのコライダがまだ衝突中であるため
two colliders are still in contact.
数回これが発生していることを確認できます。
As we continue to step through
その後続けてステップ実行すると
eventually OnCollisionExit is called
最終的に二つのコライダが衝突しなくなったとき
when the two colliders are no longer
OnCollisionExit が
in contact.
コールされます。
Note that for an OnCollision message to
OnCollision メッセージが送信されるためには
to be sent, one of the two objects colliding
衝突する二つのオブジェクトの一つに
must have a rigidbody component.
Rigidbody コンポーネントがアタッチされている必要があります。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)